export default [
    {
        "question": "Why is alcohol add on in some air brake system?",
        "answer": "To help the system from freezing in cold weather.\n",
        "options": [
            "To help the system from freezing in cold weather.\n",
            "To help reduce speed in emergency.                            ",
            "It exhausts air to release the spring parking brakes quicker.                            ",
            "To help to more braking power in winter.                             "
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "If 40 PSI is excreted against a diaphragm of 30 square inch area, what is the total force which could be excreted?",
        "answer": "1200 lb. of force.",
        "options": [
            "800 lb. of force. \n                             ",
            "1200 lb. of force.",
            "7200 lb. of force.                            ",
            "2400 lb. of force.                             "
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "On a tractor and double trailer, what is the maximum air lost during one minute.",
        "answer": "6 PSI.\n",
        "options": [
            "6 PSI.\n",
            "5 PSI.                            ",
            "4 PSI.                            ",
            "3 PSI.                             "
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Spring brakes are most \"useful as?",
        "answer": "Hydraulic Parking brakes.\n",
        "options": [
            "Hydraulic Parking brakes.\n",
            "Anti-lock braking system.                            ",
            "Front wheel brakes.                            ",
            "Rear wheel brakes.                             "
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "How are spring types parking brakes held in release position?",
        "answer": "By air pressure.",
        "options": [
            "By spring pressure. \n                             ",
            "By application pressure.                            ",
            "By air pressure.",
            "By hand valve.                             "
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "In the interest of safety, the final responsibility to ensure that the braking system is operational, rests with?",
        "answer": "The driver.",
        "options": [
            "The maintenance crews. \n                             ",
            "The driver.",
            "The company or owner.                            ",
            "Dispatcher                             "
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "How is heat that is generated by the air brakes dissipated?",
        "answer": "Absorbed by the brake drums and dissipated into the atmosphere.",
        "options": [
            "Dissipated by the air temperature. \n                             ",
            "Dissipated by the speed of the vehicle.                            ",
            "Absorbed by the brake drums and dissipated into the atmosphere.",
            "Dissipated by the weight of the vehicle.                             "
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Tractor protection system consist of?",
        "answer": "Trailer air supply valve and tractor protection valve.\n",
        "options": [
            "Trailer air supply valve and tractor protection valve.\n",
            "To help reduce speed in emergency.                            ",
            "If air lost brakes will dynamite immediately.                            ",
            "All of the above.                             "
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "An automatic front wheel limiting valve will deliver equal pressure to the front and rear brakes when application pressure exceeds?",
        "answer": "60 PSI.",
        "options": [
            "80 PSI. \n                             ",
            "60 PSI.",
            "45 PSI.                            ",
            "30 PSI.                             "
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the maximum air pressure available?",
        "answer": "Reservoir pressure (Main reservoir) (supply reservoir)",
        "options": [
            "Secondary reservoir. \n                             ",
            "Pressure in the service line.                            ",
            "Reservoir pressure (Main reservoir) (supply reservoir)",
            "Primary reservoir.                             "
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Spring parking brakes are most useful as?",
        "answer": "A mechanical parking brakes.",
        "options": [
            "A reserve brake if the service brake fails. \n                             ",
            "A mechanical parking brakes.",
            "An emergency stopping device.                            ",
            "All of the above.                             "
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "The trailer supply valve must shut off air pressure?",
        "answer": "20 PSI and 45 PSI\n",
        "options": [
            "20 PSI and 45 PSI\n",
            "50 PSI to 90 PSI                            ",
            "105 PSI to 125 PSI                            ",
            "60 PSI to 100 PSI                             "
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "How do you know you are turning the slack adjuster adjusting bolt in the correct direction when adjusting the brakes?",
        "answer": "Always turn the adjusting bolt the same way as the application rotation.",
        "options": [
            "Always turn the adjusting block in a counter clockwise rotation. \n                             ",
            "Always turn the adjusting bolt in a clockwise rotation.                            ",
            "Always turn the adjusting bolt the same way as the application rotation.",
            "Always turn the adjusting bolt in anti-clockwise.                             "
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "When a trailer is disconnected and left parked, you should?",
        "answer": "Block the wheel.",
        "options": [
            "Make sure the trailer brake is dynamited. \n                             ",
            "Block the wheel.",
            "Make sure brakes are properly adjusted.                            ",
            "Dump airbags.                             "
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "In a dual air brake system, if you have primary brake failure which brake you can still operate?",
        "answer": "The front axle brake.\n",
        "options": [
            "The front axle brake.\n",
            "The rear axle brakes.                            ",
            "Hand brake.                            ",
            "Spring brakes.                             "
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "What are three functions of the slack adjuster?",
        "answer": "Connection between Push Rod and S-Cam, brake adjustment, mechanical lever.\n",
        "options": [
            "Connection between Push Rod and S-Cam, brake adjustment, mechanical lever.\n",
            "Brake adjustment, anti-compound device, mechanical lever.                            ",
            "Anti-compound device, connection between push rod and S-Cam, brake adjustment.                            ",
            "A and C                             "
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the main purpose of a hand valve?",
        "answer": "To control independently the amount of air application to be directed to the trailer brakes.",
        "options": [
            "To control independently the amount of air application to be directed to the tractor brakes. \n                             ",
            "To act as an emergency brake if foot valve fails.                            ",
            "To control independently the amount of air application to be directed to the trailer brakes.",
            "To park the trailer.                             "
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which are the common measures of air pressure?",
        "answer": "Pound per square inch and kilo pascal.",
        "options": [
            "Ponds and kilogram. \n                             ",
            "centimeter and millimeter                            ",
            "Pound per square inch and kilo pascal.",
            "Revolution per minute.                             "
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "What causes moisture to form in the air brake system?",
        "answer": "Compressed air becomes hot, then cools creating moisture.",
        "options": [
            "Air coolant leaking into the system. \n                             ",
            "Air warms in the supply wet tank, creating moisture.                            ",
            "Compressed air becomes hot, then cools creating moisture.",
            "Not drain Supply tank properly.                             "
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "When air pressure in the reservoir is at maximum, the compressor?",
        "answer": "Governor is unloaded.\n",
        "options": [
            "Governor is unloaded.\n",
            "Is stopped.                            ",
            "Is uncoupled.                            ",
            "Governor loaded.                             "
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "An anti-lock brake system is one that?",
        "answer": "All of the above.",
        "options": [
            "Modulates braking force if wheel lock up is sensed during braking. \n                             ",
            "Helps the driver retain control during heavy braking on slippery roads.                            ",
            "Is a system of sensors of solenoid valves controlled by an electronic control unit (ECU)                            ",
            "All of the above."
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "In which direction should the adjusting nut (bolt) be turned to tighten the brakes?",
        "answer": "Make the S-Cam shaft rotate in the same direction as brake application.",
        "options": [
            "Clockwise. \n                             ",
            "Make the S-Cam shaft rotate in the same direction as brake application.",
            "Same direction as the S-Cam.                            ",
            "Anti-Clockwise.                             "
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "If the brakes are out of adjustment, what is the force of the spring brakes when applied?",
        "answer": "Less.",
        "options": [
            "The same. \n                             ",
            "Greater.                            ",
            "Less.",
            "Not Grater not less.                             "
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the fine for operating a commercial vehicle with brakes improperly adjusted?",
        "answer": "Possible fine up to $ 2000.",
        "options": [
            "Driver placed out of service for 10 hours. \n                             ",
            "Possible fine up to $ 2000.",
            "Possible fine up to $ 5000.                            ",
            "Up to $ 10000                             "
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Sludge may form which can accumulate in the bottom of the reservoir, what is the cause of sludge?",
        "answer": "Oil leaks in the compressor.",
        "options": [
            "Air leak in primary reservoir. \n                             ",
            "Air leak in Supply reservoir.                            ",
            "Oil leaks in the compressor.",
            "Dirt enter in air dryer.                             "
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the purpose of the brake chamber?",
        "answer": "Converts the compressed air force into strong mechanical force.",
        "options": [
            "To adjust manual slack adjuster. \n                             ",
            "To adjust automatic slack adjuster.                            ",
            "Release and apply brakes quicker.                            ",
            "Converts the compressed air force into strong mechanical force."
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "When the governor discharge valve opens, it is to?",
        "answer": "Stop the compressor pumping air.\n",
        "options": [
            "Stop the compressor pumping air.\n",
            "Start the compressor pumping air.                            ",
            "Turns on low air warning.                            ",
            "Brake dynamite immediately.                             "
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Where is air dry unit installed?",
        "answer": "Between the compressor and first reservoir.",
        "options": [
            "Between primary and secondary reservoir. \n                             ",
            "Between governor and compressor                            ",
            "Between the compressor and first reservoir.",
            "Between compressor and primary reservoir.                             "
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "How is heat dissipated that is generated by the brakes?",
        "answer": "Absorbed by the brake drums and dissipated into the atmosphere.",
        "options": [
            "Dissipated by the air temperature. \n                             ",
            "Dissipated by the speed of the vehicle.                            ",
            "Absorbed by the brake drums and dissipated into the atmosphere.",
            "Dissipated by the weight of the vehicle.                             "
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "In most trailers the reservoir is filled with air through the?",
        "answer": "Relay emergency valve.",
        "options": [
            "Treadle valve. \n                             ",
            "Relay emergency valve.",
            "The service lines.                            ",
            "Wet tank (supply tank)                             "
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Power to move and power to stop?",
        "answer": "Heavy tractor-trailer will take longer to accelerate (move) and a lot longer to stop.\n",
        "options": [
            "Heavy tractor-trailer will take longer to accelerate (move) and a lot longer to stop.\n",
            "Heavy tractor-trailer will take less time to move and less time to stop.                            ",
            "Use air to move and hard brakes to stop.                            ",
            "All of the above.                             "
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "The final responsibility to ensure that the braking system is operational rest on?",
        "answer": "The driver.",
        "options": [
            "The company. \n                             ",
            "The dispatcher.                            ",
            "The driver.",
            "The mechanic.                             "
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "If one set of brake is poorly adjusted?",
        "answer": "The other brakes must be increasing their braking effort and may overheat.",
        "options": [
            "Reduce rear brake application by 50%. \n                             ",
            "The other brakes must be increasing their braking effort and may overheat.",
            "Reduce front brake application by 75%.                            ",
            "Nothing will happen other brakes still working.                             "
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Why is a 30 long stroke brake chamber designed?",
        "answer": "Allow type 30 brakes two stroke 2-3 inches.\n",
        "options": [
            "Allow type 30 brakes two stroke 2-3 inches.\n",
            "Allow type 30 brakes two stroke 1-2 inches.                            ",
            "Allow faster release.                            ",
            "None of all                             "
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the main purpose of air compressor?",
        "answer": "The source of energy for the air brake system.",
        "options": [
            "It makes the air. \n                             ",
            "Controls the pressure warning.                            ",
            "The source of energy for the air brake system.",
            "To provide air for move truck.                             "
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "If the foot valve and the hand valve are operated at the same time, the trailer application pressure will be?",
        "answer": "The highest pressure being applied by hand valve or foot valve.",
        "options": [
            "The foot valve application pressure. \n                             ",
            "The hand valve application pressure.                            ",
            "The highest pressure being applied by hand valve or foot valve.",
            "The lowest pressure being applied by hand valve or foot valve.                             "
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "If the speed of the vehicle is doubled, how many times must the stopping power be increased to be able to stop in the same distance?",
        "answer": "Four times.",
        "options": [
            "Two times. \n                             ",
            "Eight times.                            ",
            "Four times.",
            "Ten times.                             "
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "When a driver release foot valve, air pressure exhausted from?",
        "answer": "Foot valve, Quick release valve and relay valve.",
        "options": [
            "Foot valve and hand valve. \n                             ",
            "One way check valve and two-way check valve.                            ",
            "Hand valve and relay valve.                            ",
            "Foot valve, Quick release valve and relay valve."
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "To control speed on a downgrade, it is good practice to?",
        "answer": "Select correct gear with small even brake application.",
        "options": [
            "Use hard brakes to slow the speed. \n                             ",
            "Select high gear with small brake applications.                            ",
            "Select correct gear with small even brake application.",
            "Select high gear with engine brakes.                             "
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Spring Brake applied by spring pressure and release by?",
        "answer": "Air Pressure.",
        "options": [
            "Hand Valve \n                             ",
            "Foot valve.                            ",
            "Emergency relay valve.                            ",
            "Air Pressure."
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "If the trailer brakes away, the purpose of the tractor protection valve is to?",
        "answer": "To prevent loss of air from the tractor.",
        "options": [
            "To prevent loss of air from the trailer. \n                             ",
            "To prevent loss of air from the tractor.",
            "Reduce front brake application by 75%.                            ",
            "Nothing will happen until brakes apply.                             "
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "What will occur if the supply line ruptures?",
        "answer": "The trailer brakes will dynamite immediately. *",
        "options": [
            "The trailer brake will dynamite after a hand or foot brake application. \n                             ",
            "All the air in the trailer will be lost.                            ",
            "The trailer brakes will dynamite immediately. *",
            "Nothing will happen until brakes apply.                             "
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "What causes moisture to form in the air brake system?",
        "answer": "Compressed air becomes hot, then cool, creating condensation.",
        "options": [
            "Engine coolant leaking into the system. \n                             ",
            "Air warm up in the wet tank creating condensation.                            ",
            "Compressed air becomes hot, then cool, creating condensation.",
            "Brakes are cool.                             "
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "How can some parking brakes be released without the use of air pressure?",
        "answer": "Mechanically, with a bolt.",
        "options": [
            "A spring brakes pressure. \n                             ",
            "Mechanically, with a bolt.",
            "With the hand and foot valve brake application.                            ",
            "By compounding.                             "
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the purpose for relay valve?",
        "answer": "To get air to brake quicker for faster braking.",
        "options": [
            "To release the brakes quickly. \n                             ",
            "To get air to brake quicker for faster braking.",
            "To apply the trailer brake.                            ",
            "To apply and release brake.                             "
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "The speed at which a vehicle should travel on a downgrade is best determined by?",
        "answer": "The necessity to make an emergency stop.\n",
        "options": [
            "The necessity to make an emergency stop.\n",
            "The source of energy for the air brake.                            ",
            "To ensure your engine stay below the governor RPM.                            ",
            "The amount of speed.                             "
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the advantage of a dual circuit air system?",
        "answer": "To prevent total brake failure.",
        "options": [
            "To reduce brake lining wear. \n                             ",
            "To improve braking effort.                            ",
            "To prevent total brake failure.",
            "For safe braking.                             "
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "In a tractor- trailer combination vehicle on a full brake application with maximum air pressure air loss should not exceed?",
        "answer": "4 PSI.",
        "options": [
            "2 PSI. \n                             ",
            "4 PSI.",
            "6 PSI                            ",
            "3 PSI.                             "
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "What is meant by the term “friction”?",
        "answer": "The force which resists movement between two surfaces in contact with each other.",
        "options": [
            "The factor that stops the vehicle. \n                             ",
            "The factor that moves the vehicle.                            ",
            "The force which resists movement between two surfaces in contact with each other.",
            "A and B                             "
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "In the interest of safety, who ensures the braking system is operational?",
        "answer": "The Driver.\n",
        "options": [
            "The Driver.\n",
            "The maintenance crew.                            ",
            "The company owner.                            ",
            "Mechanic.                             "
        ]
    }
]